You're special.
You have a very special purpose in life.
You've been chosen.
The Island awaits you.
I'm fine, I'm fine, I'm fine.
Good morning, Tower One.
Exterior contamination index
is 85 percent.
Sunny and mild.
Hey, I'm missing a left shoe.
And when you get a chance,
I'd like another color.
- Morning.
- Hey, Lincoln. How you doing?
- I'm missing a shoe.
- Hey, you're cutting.
- Yeah.
Thank you.
We're full.
Good morning. July 19, 2019.
Another day in paradise.
Starkweather Two Delta,
your time has come.
You're moving out to The Island.
Starkweather Two Delta here.
And as you know, the biggest dream
of my life just came true.
I mean, I've only been with you guys for,
like, six months, but I won the lottery.
- That's right, me.
- Six months.
To go out and breathe fresh air.
Swim in the ocean.
I can 't believe I won.
You call me Mr. Popular, I know.
It's me. It's me.
You guys know I'm not like this,
but this is just amazing.
I'm going to The Island!
We're gonna have so much fun!
But I need to see you guys out there.
You can do it. I won!
That was this week's winner...
We got a disturbance on elevator 12,
plaza level.
- Just moments before his final
departure to The Island
nature's last remaining
pathogen-free zone.
Lucky guy, huh? Don't you think?
The next lottery is tonight.
"The next lottery is tonight."
- How long have you been here?
- Two years.
- What about you?
- Three.
Three. I've been here seven.
If I do the math, that makes me
the biggest lottery loser in the room.
I'm such a loser.
Sir.
Yeah, you.
Swipe.
Gandu Three Echo. You've been flagged
for public disturbance before.
Yes, I had a very small
emotional outburst, sir.
- Safe to say it's over?
- Yes, very safe.
I'm feeling much better.
- Then have a pleasant day.
- You too.
You both have a pleasant day too.
Stretch.
One more breath in.
- Listen.
- I tried to do better.
Remember, be polite,
pleasant and peaceful.
A healthy person is a happy person.
Lincoln Six Echo, choices are fruit,
oatmeal and any type of bran.
No bacon today?
You got a nutrition flag.
Means no bacon.
Then I'll have two eggs, over easy,
not too runny, and a side of sausages.
Maybe some French toast
and a little powdered sugar.
You ain't cute and I got no time
for your lip, Six Echo.
- Now, what's it gonna be?
- Move it.
Surprise me.
Surprise.
Yummy. Next.
Watch and learn.
Next.
Jordan Two Delta.
- Hi, honey.
- Hi.
Choices are powdered eggs,
dried fruit and yogurt.
- Eggs, please.
- Okay.
So where were you the other day?
We missed you.
That's nice of you to say, sweetheart.
Get you anything else?
Maybe a little bacon.
- No, it says I shouldn't.
- Go ahead.
Four... Five pieces, please.
Thank you.
- I softened her up for you.
- No doubt.
Back on your diet, huh?
You kidding? I love this.
Better eat up.
You'll need your strength tonight.
- Is that a challenge?
- I promise I'll go easy on you.
Please separate. Find your seats now.
"'Who wants Sally? ' said Dick.
'I do,' said Jane.
'I cannot find Sally.
Get up, Dick.
Get up and help me find Sally.'
'Is Sally here? '"
Dr. Merrick will see you now.
What did you do wrong this time,
tough guy?
Sir?
You wanted to see me?
Yes. Please.
Please sit down.
So how is Lincoln Six Echo today?
Not so good, I guess.
Why do you say that?
Well, if I'm here,
it means I'm not so good.
That's a rather negative association.
My only job is to see that you're happy,
that things are okay with you.
Right.
Your file shows that you've been
interacting regularly
with Jordan Two Delta.
There's no law against friendship.
No, we encourage it, but obviously,
proximity could become a concern.
I know the rules of proximity.
You've been doing quite well
in most other areas.
Proficient at work,
exercising rigorously.
But screening has picked up
some trace levels
changes in your metabolism,
and you've been having nightmares.
Are you saying there's something
wrong with me?
Why don't you tell me
about your dream.
Well, it's the same dream every time.
I'm on a boat, headed to The Island.
A boat? What kind of boat?
A nice boat.
Draw it for me, would you?
So you're heading toward The Island.
What happens then?
I drown.
Really?
Why do you think that is?
I don't know. You tell me.
- Are you afraid of winning?
- Why would I be afraid?
You tell me.
What's troubling you, Lincoln?
Well, it's...
It's just...
All right. Tuesday night is tofu night
and I'm asking myself, "Who decided
that everyone here likes tofu?"
And what is tofu, anyway?
And why can't I have bacon?
I line up every morning and I'm not
allowed bacon for my breakfast.
And tell me...
Let's talk about all the white.
Why is everyone
always wearing white?
It's impossible to keep clean.
I always get the gray stripe.
I never get any color.
And I hand it in to be cleaned,
and someone cleans it
and folds it neatly back in my drawer,
but who?
Who is that person? I don't know.
I just... I wanna know answers,
and I wish that there was more.
More?
Yeah. More than just waiting
to go to The Island.
Lincoln
it's your nature to question things.
But don't you realize
how lucky you are?
That you survived the contamination.
That nature has left you
a Garden of Eden to repopulate.
That, Lincoln, is your purpose.
Right. And you?
Aren't you going to The Island too?
No.
My responsibility is to make sure
this facility continues to operate.
That's why people like me,
my staff and supervisors, we...
We can't win the lottery.
Let me see that.
You draw well.
"Renovatio."
- What does that mean?
- I don't know. It's always in my dream.
I'd like to run some tests
on you, Lincoln.
- What sort of tests?
- Nice tests.
Come with me.
Take a seat.
Okay, let's get you comfortable.
Swing back.
- I thought these were nice tests.
- It's a synaptic brain scan.
Totally harmless.
Don't worry, it's painless.
- It hurts.
- Not really.
- Yeah, it does!
- No, it doesn't.
Yeah, it really, really does!
The microsensors will move along
your optic nerve.
They'll be uploading readings to us
over the next 24 hours
after which you'll pass them
through your urine.
Now, that might hurt.
Six Echo, you're late.
- Jones, you ever get bored doing this?
- Doing what?
- This.
- I never really thought about it.
- I think about it a lot.
- About what?
This boring job.
What are we doing here, anyway?
We're feeding the nutrient lines.
We eat food,
food's gotta have vitamins, right?
- It's good for us.
- You don't ever wonder about anything?
Where do these tubes go?
They start there.
And they go... right there.
Hey, did you get a look
at the new guy?
Seven Foxtrot.
They found another survivor.
- They keep finding them.
- He'll probably win the lottery tomorrow.
Straight down, in the hole.
There you go, you try it.
Straight down.
- In...
- In the hole.
In the hole. No, no. No. No.
Put it down.
Did we look that stupid when
we went through decontamination?
Hey, Mr. Man-With-All-the-Questions,
let me ask you this.
- Lottery's supposed to be random, right?
- Right.
What if it's not? What if it's rigged?
Rigged?
I've been working on this. Here.
Take a look at that.
It charts the last 20 people
that won a spot on The Island.
Excluding, of course, the women,
picked to be breeders.
- What is this?
- I took the first letter in each name.
I assigned it a point value
based on its alphabet position.
Like the last, Starkweather,
S equals 15.
Q equals 15, S equals 19.
Do you see what I'm saying?
- No.
- Maybe if you would listen to me.
I'm trying to tell you.
You string the numbers together.
You divide it by the amount...
You multiply it by the amount...
You divide it by the amount of peop...
Divide by the amount
of people here.
Which is 25... A thousand plus 5... 2500.
You know what that spells?
J-O-N-E-S.
- I'm winning the lottery tonight.
- Did you pack?
- No.
- Gentlemen
I'm gonna go mess with Foxtrot.
There you go. Straight...
Straight down, in the hole.
There you go.
- He had something on his...
- Go.
Lima! Are you okay?
Code 15! We need med-techs
down here, stat! Lima One Alpha.
Just give her some air, okay?
You're gonna be okay.
Just relax and breathe.
Can I get a wheelchair down here,
please? It's for Lima One Alpha.
I think it's time.
Lima. You're going to The Island.
- We're going.
- Oh, you're so lucky.
I hope I see you soon.
Everyone, please follow her out.
Quickly and carefully.
Watch the glass.
- Good luck, Lima.
- Thank you.
That's fair. That's real fair.
Ladies, push back, please.
Gentlemen, thank you.
Everyone, back to work.
That is so not fair!
Oh, man, I hate this jealousy thing.
It's giving me heart palpitations.
Tech Services.
Computer's down again.
I'm down.
Computer guy's in Sector Six.
I have to deal with this mess.
Take my Tri-key.
- Contamination kit. Hurry back.
- Absolutely.
- Hey! What are you doing?
- I'm gonna see this guy.
Hey, we've got live wires
all over the place here.
Hey, I've been looking all over for you.
- What?
- I've been looking all over...
- Can't hear you.
- I've been looking all over for you.
If you go and get yourself contaminated,
don't come pointing the finger at me.
- How you doing, Mac?
- What are you doing here?
My chip fried again.
Yeah, your chip fried. How much longer
you think that one's gonna work?
What are you clowns looking at?
Hey, got any of that stuff
on you today?
Oh, look, it's break time. Come on.
You're a bad influence on me.
Must be why I like you so much.
What's it like where you live?
In Sector Five?
Well, it's fine. You know,
it's like any other sector, I guess.
I like coming out here, talking.
Most supervisors don't like to talk.
Yeah.
Step into my office.
- Are these your friends?
- Yeah, sometimes.
Where are their clothes?
Hey, what's with Dr. Merrick?
You mean, why does he act like he's got
a filing cabinet shoved up his ass?
- Yeah.
- It's called a "God complex."
Doctors are like that.
Think they know everything.
What's God?
You know when you want something
really bad and you wish for it?
God's the guy that ignores you.
Oh, right.
Tech service requested
in Product Extraction.
Yeah, I'll be right there.
Oh, hey, let me get that.
Where do you get that stuff, anyway?
It's an old stash.
You know, from before.
You mean from before
the contamination?
Yeah. Come on,
you're killing me with questions here.
You got a sweet deal here, you know?
Because you're, you know,
like, special.
Why? Why am I special?
There's another question.
You remember what we talked about?
You don't tell anybody about our talks?
- No.
- That'll get me in big trouble.
No, I don't.
Good.
Hey, how are you?
How's your world?
Okay, I'll catch you later.
Chinese junk locked up again, huh?
Yep.
What a surprise.
Go hot.
- You better fix that thing.
- Yeah.
You'd think with the money they make,
they could afford decent equipment.
Yeah. Ready?
Cut the O2.
Seriously, unless you wanna see me
blow chunks, can you wait till I'm gone?
- Sever the umbilical.
- Cutting.
Breathe!
Come on, yeah. That's it.
Come on, breathe.
Come on.
Come on, come on!
Breathe, breathe!
There we go. Now we're working.
He's healthy.
Welcome to the world.
- So how's Three Hilo?
- Good.
He's feisty. Light.
Vitals seem fine.
- Smooth extraction?
- Yep.
Looks like we have a fine product.
Tag him and ship him to Foundation.
Little bug.
Next time I won't embarrass you
in front of your friends.
It was very sad.
- Hey.
- Hello.
Hi.
You just let a little girl
beat you, huh?
Stim units restricted.
Yeah, yeah. I'll have the veggie stuff.
Papassian petal juice, please.
It's good for the skin.
Jordan, are you sick?
When I was in Dr. Merrick's office,
I thought I saw your name on a file.
No, I'm fine.
Okay.
How are you?
I'm fine.
Lincoln, I can tell when you lie because
your mouth smiles but your eyes don't.
- I found something.
- What?
- A bug.
- A bug?
- A flying bug.
- Can I see it?
I think it came in the ventilation shaft.
But they went extinct
with the contamination.
I know. And how did it get
by the pathogen sensors?
- It must be too small.
- No, it's not too small.
How did it survive out there, anyway?
How does anyone survive?
They keep finding people and bringing
them here. From where?
It's good that they find survivors.
Why do you always question the good?
You only think about the bad.
I just have a feeling
that something is wrong.
Good things do happen.
I wanna see that bug.
Hey, Gandu learned a new word
from the censor.
- What?
- "Dude."
- "Dude"? What does it mean?
- I don't know. He just called me "dude."
- Hey, dude.
- He said, "Hey, dude"?
Hey, dude. D-O-O-D. "Dood."
- Hey, dood.
- Dood.
Lottery's starting.
- Like you stand a chance.
- Dude.
Light up all etherscreens.
And start the lottery.
Good evening. Live from Ether-Con,
welcome to the lottery spin.
It's been a busy week.
We've had a record two winners
so far.
Tonight's winner will be selected
at random for relocation to The Island
transported to the world's
last paradise.
- And start the spin.
- And now let the spin begin.
Jordan Two Delta.
Step up, your time has come.
You're moving out to The Island.
For everyone else, never lose hope.
Thank you. Thank you.
I can't believe it.
I have to go in the morning.
You were right.
Good things do happen.
I wish I'd known you better.
You two. Watch your proximity.
I'll see you on The Island.
You want to go to The Island.
Breathe!
You've been chosen.
The Island awaits you.
She's so beautiful.
I've never seen a baby.
- Can I hold her?
- Not just yet.
We're going to The Island?
Oh, my God.
Congratulations, it's a beautiful girl.
- Oh, my gosh.
- Thank you.
- My baby. Oh, my gosh.
- Whenever you're ready
we have copies of your policy
termination for your records.
Look at her. She's beautiful.
Starkweather? That cute football player
on the Reebok commercials?
I love him! Is he in there?
I thought that was him, girl!
I just love him.
That's great.
Listen, you're a real hoot.
Any chance I can make this pickup?
Well, he's still in surgery. Sorry.
Lady, I've got a bird on the pad
and a storm's coming in.
We don't fly in bad weather.
They look real busy,
so I'd have a seat.
Grim Reaper coming in here
with an attitude.
Heart rate, 102. BP, 126/82.
- All right, laser cutter ready?
- It's ready.
- Make sure suction's functioning.
- Ventilating easily.
- Very good.
- Grid in place.
Prepare that bone saw.
I think we're about ready to open.
Let's clean that drip.
Doctor, heart rate's rising.
Heart rate's still rising, doctor.
- What's his blood pressure?
- BP, 138/92.
- Heart rate's still rising.
- Boost the anesthetic level.
He's fighting the ventilator.
I don't wanna have to euthanize
this guy to get his liver.
Oh, my God!
Stop that man! Get him!
Stop!
Relax. Relax, big guy.
Easy, easy! Don't damage him!
No! I don't wanna die! No!
I want to go to The Island!
You promised!
I wanna live! I don't wanna die!
No!
Hey. You okay, buddy?
It's not the first time
this has happened, you know.
Ether-Con. Product is secure.
Check this part out.
Wait. Okay, watch. Wait, wait, wait.
Boom! Did you see that?
Man. That is so cruel, man.
Oh, man. Down for the count.
Gentlemen.
I understand there's been an incident.
Sir, Starkweather ran
from the operating theater.
- And you find that funny?
- No, sir.
- Do you?
- Definitely not, sir.
Play it back, please.
Stop.
- Who is that?
- That's just an RN.
He was scared. I helped him up.
Play it back at half-speed.
Freeze.
Magnify his wrist.
We have a product on the loose.
- Get me a facial match.
- We're on it.
- Let's go.
- Okay, down to Level Two.
- How sweet. You came to...
- You gotta come with me.
Move! Move!
We got a match! Lincoln Six Echo.
I want a full contamination lockdown.
Find Six Echo.
Everybody, masks down.
- What the hell?
- I need to see all your faces.
I don't care what he says.
That's live human tissue.
- Seal that liver now.
- Check the back corners.
How did that agnate get upstairs
into the Medical Sector?
Find out.
What are you doing?
Men can't be in this...
- You gotta trust me. I saw them.
- Who?
- Lima and Starkweather. They're dead.
- What?
They killed her and cut him open.
Stop it! I wanna go back to my room.
- You can't. They'll kill you.
- I'm going to The Island.
- Jordan, there is no Island! Come on!
- No.
I got Six Echo in Female Tower,
floor 32.
- He's got a female product in tow.
- Track that.
Get out of the way! Watch out.
Move! Move!
Out of the way. Get out. Now.
Just trust me.
This is a community bulletin.
Attention, residents.
A contamination alert
has been issued for Lincoln Six Echo.
Anyone coming in contact with him
will be quarantined.
Faster! Move!
Freeze! Stop right there!
Get out of the way!
- Go, go!
- Get out of the way!
I've got two agnates on the move
on the second floor.
There they are!
I've got them
in the Sector Six basement!
Get them!
- No!
- Stop!
Lincoln!
No! Stop it!
No!
You've been chosen.
You have a very special purpose in life.
Chosen to survive.
You are part of a new beginning.
You're special.
You have a very special purpose in life.
You want to go to The Island.
You're a part of a new beginning.
You're special. You've been chosen.
Very special. Chosen to survive.
To carry on.
You want to go to The Island.
Go, go!
Very special.
- He's gotta be in here.
- I'm looking!
Check over here!
Watch your left! Watch your left!
Run.
He's over here.
Very special.
You want to go to The Island.
There they are.
- Lincoln!
- Come on!
Get them! Let's go!
- Move!
- Come on!
Come on, come on. Damn!
Go, go, go. Come on.
You still think there's an Island?
Come on.
Come on. Come on.
There's a door over here!
Lincoln Six Echo remains in quarantine
after contamination exposure.
Jordan Two Delta was safely transported
to her new home on The Island.
Jones Three Echo, I need you
to concentrate in this lab.
Sir, I want to focus.
I love my job. It's very interesting.
But Lincoln Six Echo
has been contaminated
and it really worries me because
he's a very good friend of mine.
And he's my only best friend.
He'll be fine, Three Echo.
Sir, I have one question.
Where do all the tubes go?
The human organism.
Unique in all the universe
in its complexity.
The product of 3 billion years
of evolution.
Prefect in every way except one.
Like all machines, it wears out.
For centuries, the idea of replenishing
the human body
has been at the forefront
of science.
I think we need to turn this bad day
into a good day.
- How?
- By selling. Sell, sell, sell.
You start, I finish.
Ladies and gentlemen
welcome to the next generation
of science:
The agnate.
An organic frame engineered
directly into adulthood
to match the client's age.
You're looking at stage one
of its development.
Within 12 months,
it will be harvest-ready
providing a carrier for your baby,
a second pair of lungs, fresh skin
all genetically indistinguishable
from your own.
And in compliance
with the eugenics laws of 2015
all our agnates are maintained
in a persistent vegetative state.
They never achieve consciousness.
They never think
or suffer or feel pain,
joy, love, hate.
It's a product, ladies and gentlemen
in every way that matters.
Not human.
This is our public-relations director,
Mr. Whitman.
He'll be happy to answer
your questions.
Once again, thank you.
Mr. Whitman.
I wanna talk about the smartest
investment you'll ever make.
And I wanna tell you how you're gonna
live 60 to 70 years longer.
Dr. Merrick, Albert Laurent,
Blackhawk Security.
You come highly recommended by
the Defense Department, Mr. Laurent.
Though I'm unaware
of your personal qualifications.
My men are ex-Delta Force. SEALs.
I was formerly with the GIGN,
French special forces.
I understand you had
a corporate theft.
Yes, that's what I told
the Defense Department.
The reality is a little more complex.
That's why I require your services.
We've had a security breach.
You have the Defense Department
at your disposal. Why call me?
Because their investment here
is sizable.
One hundred and twenty billion dollars,
to be exact.
And I can't afford for them
to reconsider.
What you tell them
is your business, doctor.
I am in the business of keeping
my clients' confidence.
Good.
Two of our products have escaped.
Impressive, considering
they're vegetative.
Well, after several years
of trial and error
we discovered that
without consciousness
without human experience, emotion
without life
the organs failed.
How long have they been missing?
Four hours and 36 minutes.
- They're on foot?
- Yes.
Wade, 1.2 miles an hour,
five-mile perimeter.
Stand by for suspect description.
- We're on it.
- Follow me.
- Come on. We gotta keep going.
- I have to stop. I can't run anymore.
- You gotta try. Come on.
- Where?
- Anywhere but here.
- But there's nothing.
Everything's dead, Lincoln.
What if we are contaminated?
Then we'd be dead.
There's no contamination.
It was a lie.
What is it?
I don't know. But it's alive.
Come on. It's mean, whatever it is.
Let's rest in here.
Jordan Two Delta sponsor, Sarah Jordan,
is in a coma after a car accident.
She's in need of multiple
organ transplants.
How long does she have?
Forty-eight hours.
Three days, maximum.
Tell me about Six Echo.
Well, he was really the first one
to question his environment
his whole existence here.
The last few months, he began
demonstrating unstable behavior
and I can't account for it.
I'm waiting on the result
of his synaptic scan.
What do they know
about the outside world?
Very little.
We control them with the memory
of a shared event.
A global contamination.
It keeps them fearful of going outside.
The Island is the one thing
that gives them hope.
Gives them purpose.
Everything we expose them to
their programs, their cartoons,
books, the games they play
are designed to manage aggression
and reinforce simple social skills.
To avoid obvious complications
they aren 't imprinted
with an awareness of sex.
We find it simpler to eliminate
the drive altogether.
In a very real sense
they're like children.
Educated to the level of a 15-year-old.
- What was that?
- I don't know.
But I want one.
Look!
Route 39. Route 39.
Come on.
I got it from a friend.
I think that's it.
What's up?
Yeah, do you know
a guy named McCord?
Yeah, we know that tool.
Who's asking?
- I am.
- And you would be who?
- Lincoln Six Echo.
- Jordan Two Delta.
Right.
Y'all some of those
desert UFO freaks?
- U...? What? No. I don't think so, no.
- No.
- McCord?
- Well, lucky day, Captain Kirk.
- He's in the can.
- He's in a can?
Taking a dump.
A dump? Taking it where?
Tell you what,
you're fixing to get on my nerves.
- It's the first door on the right.
- Thank you.
I have to go.
He's taking a dump in a can.
- Something to drink? Jack?
- Yes, please.
Straight up?
That is bitchen.
So this is Sector Five?
Hey! You son of a bitch!
You knew!
- How the hell did you get out?
- Why? Why do they lie to us? Tell me!
- They'll be looking for you.
- Tell me what's going on!
What's going on is if anybody sees us
together, both of us are gonna be dead.
So will you just take your hands off me?
Let me...
Let me pull my pants up.
I'll take you back to my place
so we can be alone, okay?
- Ed.
- Mac.
Give you boys a minute?
What? This isn't what it looks like.
Sure. Sure.
Get out of here, you stupid...
Will you stop?
You can't just bust in on a guy like that.
That's really rude.
She doesn't understand licking.
What are you, a knucklehead?
You brought another with you?
Excuse me. Listen, will you...?
Hey, back off, Joe, okay?
Don't push me!
No, that's no good.
Put it on my tab. We gotta go.
Friends of mine.
They're from out of town.
- Let's go.
- Give me your number.
- Two Delta.
- Hey. Don't test me.
Don't.
Well, this is nice.
Mac doesn't talk much
about his work at the Institute.
Do y'all work with him?
Saving lives and all
must be real rewarding.
Some fancy tracksuits.
Y'all exercise out in this heat, you'll get
yourself some nasty heat stroke.
Oh, Mac.
Look, they got matching bracelets.
We should do that, honey.
Suzie.
Do you remember the talk
we had about all the talk?
Yeah.
Would you run down to Red's
and pick up a sixer of Bud?
- We gotta talk shop.
- Okay, baby.
Just making friends.
- I know. Good. Just...
- Bye.
Why do they lie, Mac?
Why do they lie to us? Tell me.
To keep you from knowing
what you are.
- What we are?
- What are we?
Man, why do I gotta be the guy that
tells the kids there's no Santa Claus?
Okay, look. You're...
Well, you're not like me.
I mean, you're not human.
I mean, you're human, but you're just...
You're not real.
You're not like a real person.
Like me.
You're clones.
You're copies of people
out here in the world.
- What?
- Clones?
- What? Why?
- What are you talking about?
Some hag trophy wife
needs new skin for a face-lift
or one of them gets sick and they
need a new part, they take it from you.
But I have a mother. I remember her.
- Yeah, I know.
- I grew up on a farm.
- I have a little dog and I had a bike.
- And a bike. Right.
It was a pink Flexi-Flyer
with little tassels on the handlebars
and you rode it
to your grandma's house.
You ring a bell. She came out,
served you cookies on a hot plate.
- Yeah.
- No. Memory imprints.
I seen them. My buddy is a programmer
at the Institute. He showed me.
There's only, like, 12 stories.
They change around little details.
But they're all pretty much the same.
The life you think you had
before the "contamination"?
It never happened.
Come on, don't look at me like that.
At least you had a bike.
Wanna trade your rosy memory implants
for my shitty childhood? Be my guest.
How long?
How long have we been alive?
You're Echo generation, so you're 3.
Delta means you're 4.
Three?
The whole reason you exist is because
everyone wants to live forever.
It's the new American dream.
There's people out there that are
rich enough to pay anything for it.
Don't people care that they kill us?
That they take parts from us?
They don't know. They think you're
vegetables simmering in a jelly sac.
Why do you think Merrick has you stuck
in an old military bunker below ground?
He doesn't want anyone knowing
the truth. Especially not your sponsors.
- Sponsors?
- The people that had you made.
They, like, own you.
But why doesn't Merrick want
our owners to know that we're alive?
Just because people eat the burger
doesn't mean they wanna meet the cow.
Besides
do you know how many laws Merrick's
breaking to have you two hatched?
Your sponsors can't have
any part of that.
They're, like, high society.
Rich and famous.
If they knew,
Merrick would be out of business.
We have to find our sponsors
and tell them the real truth.
- What? No.
- Yeah.
No. That's the worst idea
I ever heard.
You know how dead I would be?
Not to mention fired?
We will. We will.
That's our only chance.
Stop! Fold, stop. Brakes.
No. Come on.
You're like the replacement engines
on their Bentley.
They're not gonna care.
They don't care. They're gonna care?
You know what I would do
if I were you?
I would get as far away from here
as I could. Go to the beach.
We're not asking
for your permission, Mac.
We're asking for your help.
Oh, God.
Infrared's having a hard time getting
a heat signature on our fugitives.
Sand's too hot.
He was implanted
with microsensors yesterday.
Can we configure our instrument
to pick up a low-frequency RF scan?
- If we're within half a mile of the source.
- Do it.
Your sponsors' names
are Tom Lincoln and Sarah Jordan.
Her sponsor lives in New York.
The number in your name
is a regional code.
Six Echo, it means
your sponsor lives in L.A.
- You're going out of state.
- Out of state.
Yeah. Put this on. No, no, no.
You're gonna go in here.
All right? Come on, come on.
Keep going. What size?
These are bags, okay?
You put stuff in them.
Backpacks for boys, purses for girls.
Understand?
We're not idiots.
Excuse me, Miss I'm-So-Smart-
l-Can't-Wait-to-Go-to-The-Island.
Yeah. Good.
Wait. Hold. People don't really wear
these on the outside.
These are mail-order, okay?
They stay here.
No. Mail-order, okay?
Clones don't wear these.
All right. Listen up.
This card is like stim credits.
It'll get you food, but I gotta
report it stolen in 24 hours
or else they'll know I helped you.
After that, use the cash.
All right, look. I know you're new to
this whole human experience and all
but there's one universal truth
and that is you never give a woman
your credit card.
Right.
I got something. It's hot.
Train will be here in a few minutes.
Hustle up.
- And Sacramento is
now boarding at platform A.
All right, stay. All right? Just stay.
Don't move.
Look at that.
Those are kids.
Come here. The train is nonstop to L.A.
You need these to get on.
When you arrive, look up your sponsors
in the information directory. Got it?
Yeah. Yeah.
What is an information directory?
It'll tell you where they live.
And whatever you do,
do not trust anyone.
One thing I can tell you about people
is that they'll do anything to survive.
Thank you, Mac. Thank you.
Thanks a lot.
All right. I'm just gonna go upstairs
and get you guys a map of L.A.
Better not get me in trouble.
I think I got an ID. Two in the center.
Run!
Oh, God!
Amtrak train 227 now departing
for Los Angeles at platform C.
What's wrong with these people?
They killed him.
- This was supposed to be simple.
- It's never simple.
We got a missing credit card.
McCord just used it
to buy train tickets.
- It's not in his wallet.
- Monitor the account.
Have Amtrak patch you through
to the train conductor.
Get me a new team in L.A.
Got here as fast as I could.
I finished scanning the
Defense Department troop selections
if you want to see them.
- Not yet. Look at that.
- Six Echo drew it.
- Well, it's elaborate.
"Renovatio."
"Renovatio"? Renovatio.
- What is that, Italian?
- It's Latin.
We've never imprinted
an agnate with Latin.
Yes, I'm well aware of that.
So where did he learn it?
Where are the results
from his synaptic scan?
They'll be back from Johns Hopkins...
- Just speed it up.
- Yes, sir.
You two.
Over there!
We just arrived, but Troy's already
tapped into the city cameras.
Excuse me.
Where's an information directory?
Thanks.
Wilshire. Fifth. Grand.
Spring. Grand Avenue?
Smile for the camera.
Where is Flower? You on Flower?
Olive?
Come on, come on.
You look familiar. Gotcha.
Three Black Wasps and two jet bikes.
Hey! We just got a facial hit
on our fugitives!
We're moving! Let's go.
We got a hit on McCord's credit card.
Location: Grand Avenue at 9830.
- Team, proceed immediately to 9830...
- No. L.A.P.D.'s moving in.
They just flagged McCord's
credit card.
- Tom Lincoln.
- One moment, please.
Not listed.
Sarah Jordan.
- Hello?
- Yes, I'm looking for Sarah Jordan.
She's sick.
- Can I talk to her?
- She's at the hospital.
Mommy, is that you?
Jordan, let's go.
Freeze! Put your hands up!
- Get your hands up!
- Put your hands up!
Do as I say! Do as I say!
- Lincoln!
- Just do what they say.
Lincoln.
Just pull back!
Nail it! Quick! Move!
We're detaining you for
the murder of James McCord.
He was helping us!
He was my friend.
Anything you say can be used
in a court of law.
What's a court of law?
They'll run DNA.
If the agnates are booked, it'll implicate
your clients in a murder investigation.
This is a nightmare.
You cannot allow this to happen.
Do you understand me?
You use any force that is necessary.
I'm ordering you to contain
the situation.
One-Adam-82. We've apprehended
the suspects. Two adults, no ID.
Notify Forensics.
We'll need DNA typing.
- My name is Tom Lincoln.
- Sit back and shut up.
- Could you look up my file, please?
- Sit back.
Dispatch, we're two minutes out.
Lincoln, get up!
Get up, Lincoln! Get up!
Let's go!
Go!
We got cops. We got cops!
Get down!
Run!
I see them! Let's get moving!
Let's go!
Come on, come on, come on!
Move, move!
Move out! Move out!
Go, go, go!
Shit! Check up here!
Air Two, give me status
of the targets.
- Targets are under the train wheels.
- Silently take them out.
Go!
Move! Go, go!
- I can't fit! I can't fit!
- Move it!
Look out, look out, look out!
Right, right, right!
Stay on them!
Look out!
Do not let him get away!
Good job.
We gotta bail out.
Police choppers inbound.
Black Wasp, take out the truck!
Troy, you all right? Let's go!
Cops! Cops!
He's coming back!
Stay down, Jordan!
- How do you know what you're doing?
- I don't know!
Hold on!
Look out!
- Don't let me go, Lincoln!
- I got you!
- Don't let me go!
- I got you.
- Don't drop me, Lincoln!
- I got you!
- Don't drop me!
- I got you.
Hold on, Lincoln! Pull me!
Pull me!
Climb up!
If there's no way to get our fugitives
quietly, you need to take them out.
I see our targets about 70 stories up.
They're on top of the building logo.
Tough day.
Let's roll.
L.A.P.D.! Get away from the window!
Jay, you got them?
Right there, right there! Get them!
Stay there! Damn it! Stay down!
Come on!
I'm gonna swing around to get a shot.
He's coming back.
Oh, no.
Hang on. It's coming off the building.
Jesus must love you!
That was the craziest mess I ever seen!
Come on, girl.
I know Jesus loves you.
Can you keep a secret, doc?
Why, yes, of course.
There is something going on
around here.
- Something you may not even know.
- What is it?
Well, I'm not sure
that the contamination is real.
- Why do you think that?
- Okay.
Lincoln told me that he found
a flying bug in Sector Six.
Right. And I think that might be why
he thought he could leave.
Have you told anyone else about this?
No. But I'm gonna do some digging.
I'm gonna get to the bottom of this.
And when I do,
I'll share my information with you.
Thank you.
I wanna be helpful.
- I like it here.
- Good.
But I really wanna look
into the lottery too.
- Something's wrong there.
- Yeah.
You know
you were one of the first
of the Echo generation.
You're very smart.
- Yeah.
- I remember when I first came here.
A survivor, just like you.
One of the first, in fact.
It's natural, even healthy,
to question the world.
Well, you might say it's only...
Only human.
That burns!
Get me a list of all the Echos
in active population.
I saw his address. Tom Lincoln.
We'll go there when the rain stops.
- It'll be okay when we find him.
- Okay.
That little boy looked like me.
His mom's gonna die, isn't she?
I don't know.
You're lying.
It's cold.
- Go in.
- I can't.
- I'll go in.
- Jordan.
Jordan!
Hello?
Lincoln!
Oh, my God.
My name is Lincoln Six Echo.
I'm your insurance policy.
And what are you doing in my house?
Sir. Sir.
You need to see this.
It's... It's...
It's beautiful.
This is the scan of Six Echo
three years ago
before we integrated him
into the agnate population.
This is his synaptic scan
from a few days ago.
See how much
the memory's grown.
It's like he's experienced 30 years,
not three, which is impossible.
Or maybe this is scarring from
a cortical infection that we didn't...
An infection can't teach you Latin.
Nor how to fly.
They are memories.
But they're not his.
They belong to his sponsor.
I've seen you before.
- I've seen you in Maxim, Esquire...
- Maxim?
They're men's magazines.
Pictures of women with little,
tight, short...
Stories too.
Anyway, you are very popular.
There we are.
- What is that?
- Looks like some kind of thermal im...
Boy, your skin is so soft.
Did you know?
- I put some clothes out for you upstairs.
- Thank you.
No, thank you.
I keep expecting to wake up.
I thought I was taller.
I'm sorry to disappoint you.
Come here.
She is unbelievable.
How is it you've been around
three years
and get the kind of woman
I haven't found my whole life?
Give me that.
She found me. She's my best friend.
- Why do we sound different?
- I'm from Scotland.
"I'm from Scotland."
Hey, look. You're creeping me out
enough without that.
"Without that."
No, really, cut it out. That's enough.
Yeah, that is enough. I'm sorry.
Like a freak show.
Yeah, it's weird.
So you build boats?
Yeah. Well, I design them.
I draw them. Yeah, yeah.
Here.
I started off with cars, motorcycles,
experimental designs.
Anything that blew my hair back.
Kind of a speed freak.
Petrol-head.
Motorcycles. It's weird.
I feel like I've seen these before.
Yeah, it's something I've always done.
I never dreamt it would make me rich.
- What's "renovatio"?
- Renovatio in Latin means "rebirth."
Subtle, eh?
Look. I have cirrhotic hepatitis
a parting gift from God
for all my philandering.
What?
Lots and lots of sex.
- Sex?
- Sex. With...
You've ne... You're a virgin?
You're kicking around with her
and you're a virgin?
Okay, I'm not gonna spoil the surprise.
Boy, are you in for a treat.
Look, my doctor said that my liver will
start failing within the next two years.
I'm not good at all this shite, you know?
Confessions and regrets.
Look. There are people who are
following us, trying to kill us.
The reason we came is
we need your help.
- Help you do what?
- To show people what the Institute does.
I'm looking at you in the face,
and I don't believe it.
Who is that guy? I know him.
Is he the community announcer?
He's the president of America.
- He has a clone.
- He's an absolute idiot.
Yeah, I never liked him either.
- Do a lot of people see this?
- The news? A lot.
If we can get on there together, people
will see, and they'll know the truth.
So we both just waltz down to NBC
and see if they can slot us in?
This might not mean anything to you,
but there are thousands of us.
Everyone we've ever known
is gonna die in that place.
Help us.
All right. Let me just get
my shoes, okay?
Tom, hurry up!
Merrick Institute.
Merrick Biotech. How may I help you?
- This is client Tom Lincoln.
- Hi.
Could you get someone
who can explain to me
why my insurance policy is
sitting downstairs on my fucking sofa?!
- Can you hold, please?
- Sure.
I'm sorry to keep you both waiting.
I was getting myself organized.
Okay, shall we go? Are you ready?
- Something's wrong.
- What?
His eyes are lying.
The same as yours do.
- You stay here.
- No, don't...
Shall we?
- Yeah.
- Is everything okay?
Yeah. She's gonna stay here
in case they don't believe us.
- Come on, we'll all go. It'll be good.
- She's gonna stay.
Good luck.
- Thank you.
- Do you like it?
- Yeah.
- I'll drive.
- No. I'll drive.
No, really.
- Do you know how?
- Yeah, I taught myself.
But you don't know the way.
Well, then you can show me.
Well, be careful.
This is a V12 '09 Caddy.
750 horsepower, $500,000 car.
Put your thumb on that.
Worth every penny.
We even have the same prints.
- What are you doing?
- Getting directions.
Hello, Mr. Lincoln.
Where would you like to go?
- KNBC news studio.
- One moment, please.
Thanks for doing this.
That's all right. I'd like to think
you'd do the same thing if you were me.
How much did I cost?
Five million dollars.
- Is that a lot?
- It's a small price to pay to cheat death.
That's a red.
- It's a red. Red! Stop the car!
- What? Why?
It's a red light! Stop the car!
What's the matter?
You wanker! It's a red light! Stop!
It means stop!
- Sorry, I didn't know.
- You said you could drive.
Well, I do know how to drive.
I just don't know what the lights mean.
I'm sorry. I'm not ready to die.
Me neither!
Go, go, go!
What are you doing? Stop!
- No.
- Stop the car now!
I'll shoot. Stop the car.
- No!
- Yes!
There's cars coming at us
in all directions!
They're shooting my car.
They've shot the engine.
They've shot my engine!
Oh, God. My nose!
Where are you going, eh?
- Get up, get up!
- Let go of me!
- Get off me!
- Come on, get up.
- Let me go!
- Get up!
No, no, no. Don't shoot him.
I need him. I need him.
No, don't shoot! He's my clone!
- I'm Tom Lincoln!
- What?
No, I'm Tom Lincoln!
He's lying. Shut up!
I own you!
He's the... I'm Tom Lincoln!
Don't point the gun at me,
you fricking idiot!
- He's the clone. Look at him!
- I'm not a clone! I'm Tom!
No, I'm Tom! He's lying!
Point it at him!
- No. I'm not.
- Shut up!
Shut up! You're a clone! Shut up!
- I'm Tom Lincoln!
- Don't, don't...
Oh, shit.
Close.
Do you think it's strange that
my insurance policy just tried to kill me?
I find this whole operation strange.
Where's the woman?
She said she was going out of state
to look for her sponsor.
You've been witness
to certain trade secrets.
You mean that they manufacture
human beings who walk, talk and feel?
That kind of secret?
Have you talked with
anyone else about this?
Who would believe it?
Can I count on that?
The only thing you can count on
is that people will do
anything to survive.
I just want to live. I don't care how.
Thank you.
Thank you very much. Job well done.
Jordan? Jordan?
Stop.
Hey, Jordan, it's me. It's me.
It's you.
- That tongue thing is amazing.
- I know. Open your mouth again.
- How come we never did this before?
- Shut up.
The Island is real.
It's us.
- How many are affected?
- About half.
We're seeing the same neural patterns
in all the Echos
plus every subsequent generation:
The Foxtrots, Gammas and Hilos.
We predicated our entire system
on predictability.
Six Echo has displayed the one trait
that undermines it:
Human curiosity.
So we're now facing
four generations
with the potential
for defiant behavior.
What are you suggesting?
A recall.
Wait. You mean dispose of over
$200 million worth of product?
- Yes.
- Great.
Cisco IP Communicator
connecting to Merrick Biotech.
Mr. Lincoln, this is Charlie Whitman
the public-relations director
at Merrick Biotech.
My deepest apologies for yesterday's
unfortunate inconvenience you had.
Your defect in your policy was
by no means an isolated incident
and it is totally correctable,
I assure you.
We are calling other valued clients
right now to inform them of a recall.
So please call us when you get...
"Unfortunate inconvenience"?
That's a bit of an understatement,
don 't you think?
Mr. Lincoln, you're home.
Aren't you traumatized, sir?
I had a home invasion once,
where they put the gun to my head.
I never forgot that.
I shook for two days.
What kind of recall
are you talking about?
It's a small defect that we found
in four of our product lines.
What are you gonna do
with the defective products?
Starting over.
- Starting over?
- Absolutely nothing to worry about.
We guarantee our product
100 percent.
The unfortunate inconvenience for you
is we'll have to bring you back in
to rescan you so that
we can regrow your policy.
Does today work for you at all?
Pick you up by helicopter at 3:00?
I'll call you back.
Dr. Merrick, how do we remove the
defective products from the population
without disrupting the others?
We already have
the mechanism in place.
Dahlgren Two Foxtrot.
Cooper Five Gamma.
Mass winnings.
He kept a journal and a lot of maps.
And after I figure out how to get that
in the water, we can get on it and...
We'll keep heading south.
We could live like real people.
Tulie Two Foxtrot.
Ginsberg Two Hilo.
We'll disappear.
Yeah.
But after.
All those people we left behind.
Jones Three Echo.
When we were escaping,
I saw this room.
If I could shut it down
they'd see the truth.
Gentlemen, there is, however, another
matter that requires board approval.
The disposal of $ 200 million
of infected product.
All in favor?
- Aye.
You've been chosen.
You're special.
Very special.
- Thank you.
- There you go.
- And what do you say to the nice lady?
- Thank you.
No. No.
Inbound, Jordan product.
- Escort her to Surgery Prep 7.
- I better say hello.
Mr. Lincoln, thank you for coming.
It's great seeing you again.
And we are so, so sorry
about this entire episode.
I wanna tell you we'll be birthing
a brand-new agnate for you
free of charge.
Won't cost you a penny.
After you. Would you like an apple?
An afternoon snack or...?
No. How long will this take?
It's gonna take about an hour.
I read that you're from Scotland.
I prefer Ireland myself.
But what part exactly in Scotland?
I realize small talk is just part of your job,
but let's cut the shite, okay?
Point taken. My apologies.
I'm just a bit of a jabberjaw.
Chatty Cathy. Turn right. This way.
I'll take her.
This is gonna be the exact same routine
as last time.
Mind the hose.
Technician will be here shortly.
Look at you, so young and successful.
I always wanted to
get into yachting myself. I...
I hear they're taking your kidneys
your lungs, your heart.
They are gonna hack you up.
Too bad.
No one is touching me.
Give me your Tri-key.
- You shot me.
- Shut up!
Give me your walkie!
Get down. Get down, now!
You all right?
Come on.
I've got this figured out. I kind of...
I messed up in one area right down there,
but on the whole it doesn't matter.
Something's happening.
Hello, sir.
Thank you for your patience.
I'm sure you're excited
to get to The Island.
If you can grab your
personal belongings, line up
and follow me, we'll be on our way.
Take this. Go.
You have to keep going. Go. Go.
- Okay.
- Go shut it down.
I love that Picasso.
Do you like Picasso, Mr. Laurent?
You delivered on your promise.
Well done. I'm very pleased. Thank you.
- What about the client? Sarah Jordan?
- She's doubtful.
Even if the transplants
are a success
her brain damage may be
too severe for any real recovery.
You took too long bringing her back.
So the girl I brought in, you're going
to harvest her, kill her anyway
even though it
won't make any difference?
That's the privilege our clients
pay for, Mr. Laurent.
Now, do excuse me,
I have business to attend to.
You know my father was part
of the Burkinabe rebellion?
And when he was killed,
me and my brothers were branded
so others would know
we were less than human.
I've seen and done things
I'm not proud of
but at some point you realize
war is a business.
So when did killing
become a business for you?
Oh, it's so much more than that.
I have discovered the Holy Grail
of science, Mr. Laurent.
I give life.
The agnates.
They're simply tools, instruments.
They have no souls.
The possibilities are endless here.
In two years' time, I will be able
to cure children's leukemia.
How many people on Earth
can say that, Mr. Laurent?
I guess just you and God.
That's the answer
you're looking for, isn't it?
Mr. Whitman has
your check downstairs.
Looks like single gunshot.
Oh, no.
Wrong wrist.
Dr. Merrick,
the body that just came in
it's the client.
Issue a security alert!
Lincoln Six Echo!
Down, down, down!
Move, move!
There's a disturbance
in the Hologram Room.
I'm on it.
I've sent censors to check
a possible attempted breach
in Hologram Control.
One after another, step into the room.
If I'm going to The Island,
why did I leave my bag?
Step right in, thank you.
Are you sure you know
what you're doing?
Is this the right way?
Are you new here?
I don't know if this is the way!
It's going to The Island?
I'm almost positive that
you're going the wrong way!
Open the door!
She said, open the door.
You could have taken over his life,
but you chose to come back.
You truly are unique, Six Echo.
My name is Lincoln!
I brought you into this world
and I can take you out of it.